Guide to the Lois Gould Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lois Gould papers
1940-2005
1970-2002
YCAL MSS 540
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
28.71
(34 boxes)
The papers include writings, correspondence, printed material, personal papers, photographs, audiovisual material and electronic files that document the writing career of Lois Gould, with the bulk of the material spanning 1970 to 2002. The collection consists chiefly of drafts of Gould's writings with related material such as notes, proofs, correspondence, promotional material, and reviews. The collection also includes files related to an unpublished magazine, Boomer, as well as notebooks, diaries, agendas, and subject files.
Gould, Lois, 1931-2002
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anthony Gould, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 9 (videotapes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 32 (original computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 33 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Lois Gould, 1931-2002
Lois Gould, American journalist and novelist whose work addressed the inner lives of women and topics such as infidelity and marital relationships, was born in Manhattan December 18, 1931 and died May 29, 2002. Among her writings are the novels Such Good Friends (1970), Necessary Objects (1972), Final Analysis (1974), A Sea-Change (1976), La Presidenta (1981), and Medusa's Gift (1991), a collection of essays titled Not Responsible for Personal Articles (1978), the memoir Mommy Dressing: A Love Story, After a Fashion (1998), and a feminist children's book X: A Fabulous Child's Story (1978).
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, 1961-2002. II. Book Files, 1966-2001. III. Boomer Magazine Files, 1999-2005. IV. Diaries, Notebooks and Agendas, 1973-2002. V. Other Papers, 1940-2002.
Scope and Contents
The papers include writings, correspondence, printed material, personal papers, photographs, audiovisual material and electronic files that document the writing career of Lois Gould, with the bulk of the material spanning 1970 to 2002. The collection consists chiefly of drafts of Gould's writings with related material such as notes, proofs, correspondence, promotional material, and reviews. The collection also includes files related to an unpublished magazine, Boomer, as well as notebooks, diaries, agendas, and subject files.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Feminism -- United States; Women -- Social conditions -- 20th Century; Audiotapes; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Videotapes; Authors -- 20th Century -- United States; Gould, Lois, 1931-2002
- Writings, 1961-2002; Series I; 16; (16 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. consists of drafts, proofs, and printed versions of writings by Lois Gould.
  - "School phobias of older children", undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Final Analysis
    - Partial draft, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Final draft complete, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - Proofs, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Not Responsible for Personal Articles, draft, copy edited text, and proofs, circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
  - So You Want To Be a Working Mother, drafts and page proofs, circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - La Presidenta
    - Draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
    - Draft, typescript (photocopy), circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
    - Draft, typescript (fragments), circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25-28)
    - Page proofs (proof-read), circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Page-proofs, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Drafts, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 32-43)
    - Proof, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Galley proofs, bound, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
    - Drafts, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 47-50)
    - Setting typescript, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 51-52)
    - Galley proofs, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 53-56)
    - Master galley proof, circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Medusa's Gift
    - Partial drafts and fragments, circa 1991 (Box 5, Folder 58-62)
    - Drafts, circa 1991 (Box 5, Folder 63-66)
    - Drafts and notes, circa 1991 (Box 5, Folder 67-72)
  - Mommy Dressing
    - Draft, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 73-74)
    - Drafts and notes, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 75-77)
    - Draft, autograph manuscript, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Artwork, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Draft, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Excerpts, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Proofs, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 82-83)
    - Page proofs, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 84-85)
    - Proofs, first pass, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 86-87)
    - Proofs, second pass, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 88-89)
    - Galley proofs, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Bound galley proof, circa 1998 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Necessary Objects, drafts, typescript, circa 1972 (Box 7, Folder 92-101)
  - No Brakes
    - Draft, autograph manuscript, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 102-103)
    - Drafts, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 104-110)
    - Proof, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Draft fragments, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 112-113)
    - Page proofs, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 114-116)
    - Galley proofs, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 117-118)
    - Cover artwork, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - "A Perfect Child's Story," drafts and storyboards, undated (Box 8, Folder 120-130)
  - Perfect & Other Likely Stories
    - "Perfect," drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "Bonding," drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - "Idle Hands," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 133-134)
    - "Six Figure Understanding," drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - "Story of Oogh," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - "Body and Soul," drafts, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - "Mother Loving," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - "Second Story," drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 139-141)
    - "X," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Unidentified drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 143-144)
    - Correspondence regarding short story collection, 1999-2002 (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - "New Versions - corrections," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - "Book," draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Book proposal and typescript, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Web correspondence, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - "Perfect: Another likely story," VHS videotapes and notes, 2002; (2 videotapes) (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - A Sea Change
    - Early draft and personal notes, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 152-153)
    - Draft, typescript (photocopy), circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 154-155)
    - Draft, typescript, corrected (partial), circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Final draft, typescript (photocopy), circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 157-158)
    - Complete edited draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Assorted drafts, typescript, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 160-162)
    - Original tissues, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Galley proofs, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Subject to Change
    - Drafts, typescript (and photocopy), corrected, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 165-168)
    - Drafts, typescript (and photocopy), corrected (fragments), circa 1988 (Box 11, Folder 169-175)
    - Drafts, typescript (and photocopy), corrected, circa 1988 (Box 11, Folder 176-177)
  - Such Good Friends
    - Draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1970 (Box 11, Folder 178-180)
    - Draft, typescript (photocopy), circa 1970 (Box 11, Folder 181-184)
    - Galley proofs, corrected, circa 1970 (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Draft, typescript (and photocopy), circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 186-188)
    - Media workshop award, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - Early draft, typescript (photocopy), circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 190-192)
  - X: A Fabulous Child's Story
    - Drafts and printed material, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - Correspondence and fan mail, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 194-196a)
    - Page proofs, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Galley proofs, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Graphics, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Correspondence regarding movie, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 200)
    - Notes, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - Permissions, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 202-203)
    - Promos, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Reviews, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 13, Folder 206-207)
  - Nonfiction book "Baby M", 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 208-209)
  - Rembar & Curtis correspondence, publishing contracts and other business correspondence
    - Business correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - Subject to Change, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 211-212)
    - "5 prior novels", 1978-1986 (Box 13, Folder 213)
    - "General", 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - Contracts, 1975-1988 (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - "Marriage 70s Style," printed version in Titters, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 216)
  - "Confessions of a Renovated House Car," drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 217)
  - "Winning the Lottery," draft and correspondence, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 218)
  - "Disappearing Acts," proofs and correspondence, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 219)
  - "Some Kinda Jazz," drafts, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 220-221)
  - "Creating a Woman's World," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 222-223)
  - "Some Kinda Jazz," drafts, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 224)
  - "How to Hold a Man by Giving Him His Freedom," drafts, printed version, and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - "Businessman," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 226)
  - Mommy Dressing, excerpt published in New York Times, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 227)
  - "Wishcraft," drafts and printed version, undated (Box 14, Folder 228)
  - "6-figure understanding," drafts and printed version (photocopy), 1976 (Box 14, Folder 229)
  - "Mother Loving," drafts and correspondence, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 230)
  - "Margaret Factor," drafts and printed version, undated (Box 14, Folder 231)
  - "Shock Around the Clock," drafts and printed version, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 232)
  - "Winking at Bimbos," drafts and printed version (photocopy), undated (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - "Businessman," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 234)
  - "Research material," printed material, undated (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - "The Trouble with Being the Supremes," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - "Fergal's Garden," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - "American Chanel," drafts, notes, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - "Growing Bold," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - "Harold Robbins," drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - "Penis, Rising," drafts, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - New York Times columns, reader's letters, 1961-1977 (Box 15, Folder 242)
  - "My Song of Ireland," draft and printed version (photocopy), undated (Box 15, Folder 243)
  - "What Beauty Lies in this Ancient Icon's Face," draft and printed version (photocopy), 1996 (Box 15, Folder 244)
  - "Edifice Rex," drafts, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 245)
  - Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 246)
  - "One Writer's Ireland," printed version (photocopy) and notes, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 247)
  - "Country Houses," draft and printed version (photocopy), undated (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - "Hers Forward," draft, undated (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Articles, printed versions, undated (Box 15, Folder 250-265)
  - Articles, printed versions, undated (Box 16, Folder 266-276)
  - Articles, published, undated (Box 16, Folder 277)
  - Articles, unpublished, undated (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - "Fathers and daughters," draft and correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - Op-ed, published and unpublished, drafts, undated (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - Obituaries, printed versions, undated (Box 16, Folder 281)
  - No Brakes, critique of work in progress, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - "The Kiss of My Nickel," draft fragment, undated (Box 16, Folder 283)
  - "Pornography for Women," correspondence and research material, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 284)
  - Fan mail, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 285)
  - Proposals, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 286)
  - Gunn Memorial Library and Museum, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 287)
  - Articles, drafts and printed versions, undated (Box 16, Folder 288)
  - Published articles, drafts and printed versions, undated (Box 16, Folder 289)
  - "Hers" column, correspondence, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 290)
  - Letters to the editors, drafts, undated (Box 16, Folder 291)
  - Book mail, 1968-1977 (Box 16, Folder 292)
  - Reviews - mail, 1973-1977 (Box 16, Folder 293)
  - Computer disk
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original disk is restricted. Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services. Disk # 20070206-1.
- Book Files, 1966-2001; Series II; 1.42; (2 boxes)
  Arranged alpabetically by title.
  Series II consists of correspondence, fan mail, notes, promotional material, and reviews relating to Gould's major works. These works include Final Analysis, La Presidenta, Medusa's Gift, Mommy Dressing: A Love Story, After a Fashion, Necessary Objects, No Brakes: a Novel, Not Responsible for Personal Articles, A Sea Change, So You Want to be a Working Mother, Subject to Change, and Such Good Friends.
  - Reviews of Lois Gould's books-compilation, undated (Box 17, Folder 294)
  - Final Analysis
    - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 295)
    - Fan mail, 1974-1978 (Box 17, Folder 296)
    - Notes, circa 1974 (Box 17, Folder 297)
    - Promotions, circa 1974 (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - Reviews, circa 1974 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Medusa's Gift
    - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 300)
    - Fan mail, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - Notes, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 302)
    - Promotions, circa 1991 (Box 17, Folder 303)
    - Reviews, circa 1991 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Mommy Dressing
    - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 17, Folder 305)
    - Fan mail, 1996-1999 (Box 17, Folder 306)
    - Notes, circa 1998 (Box 17, Folder 307)
    - Promotions, circa 1998 (Box 17, Folder 308)
    - Reviews, circa 1998 (Box 17, Folder 309)
  - Necessary Objects
    - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 310)
    - Fan mail, 1972-1983 (Box 17, Folder 311)
    - Notes, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 312)
    - Promotions, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 313)
    - Reviews, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 314)
  - No Brakes
    - Correspondence, 1991-2001 (Box 17, Folder 315)
    - Fan mail, 1996-1999 (Box 17, Folder 316)
    - Notes, circa 1997 (Box 17, Folder 317)
    - Promotions, circa 1997 (Box 17, Folder 318)
    - Reviews, circa 1997 (Box 17, Folder 319)
  - Not Responsible for Personal Articles
    - Correspondence, circa 1978 (Box 17, Folder 320)
    - Fan mail, 1978-1981 (Box 17, Folder 321)
    - Notes, circa 1978 (Box 17, Folder 322)
    - Promotions, circa 1978 (Box 17, Folder 323)
    - Reviews, circa 1978 (Box 18, Folder 324)
  - La Presidenta
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 325)
    - Fan mail, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 326)
    - Notes, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 327)
    - Promotions, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 328)
    - Reviews, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 329)
  - A Sea Change
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 330)
    - Fan mail, 1976-1978 (Box 18, Folder 331)
    - Notes, circa 1976 (Box 18, Folder 332)
    - Promotions, circa 1976 (Box 18, Folder 333)
    - Reviews, circa 1976 (Box 18, Folder 334)
  - So You Want to be a Working Mother
    - Correspondence, 1966, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 335)
    - Fan mail, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 336)
    - Notes and survey, circa 1966 (Box 18, Folder 337)
    - Reviews, circa 1966 (Box 18, Folder 338)
  - Subject to Change
    - Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 18, Folder 339)
    - Fan mail, 1988-1999 (Box 18, Folder 340)
    - Notes, circa 1988 (Box 18, Folder 341)
    - Promotions, circa 1988 (Box 18, Folder 342)
    - Reviews, circa 1988 (Box 18, Folder 343)
  - Such Good Friends
    - Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 344)
    - Fan mail, 1966-1980 (Box 18, Folder 345)
    - Notes, circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 346)
    - Promotions, circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 347)
    - Reviews, circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 348)
- Boomer Magazine Files, 1999-2005; Series III; 1; (1 box)
  Series II consists of files related to an unpublished magazine, Boomer, conceived by Lois Gould.
  - Correspondence and planning documents, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 349-350)
  - Boomer trademark, 2000-2005 (Box 19, Folder 351-352)
  - Boomer TOC & Coverlines, Microsoft Word, circa 2000
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disk #1.
  - Potential backers, 1999-2003 (Box 19, Folder 353)
  - Written contributions and ideas, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 354-357)
  - Prototype texts and business plan, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 358-359)
  - Notes, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 360)
  - Demographics, etc., circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 361)
  - "Writers," printed material and notes, circa 2000 (Box 19, Folder 362)
  - Prototype working copy, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 363)
- Diaries, Notebooks, and Agendas, 1973-2002; Series IV; 4.42; (5 boxes)
  Series IV consists of notes, notebooks, datebooks, diaries and journals. The notebooks contain drafts of writings and personal journal entries. Datebooks record Gould's appointments and activities from 1973 to 2002. The Diaries contain both original and edited versions of Gould's personal memoir.
  - Loose papers, undated (Box 20, Folder 364)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 20, Folder 365-382)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 21, Folder 383-390)
  - 1975 datebook (Box 21, Folder 391)
  - 1976 datebook (Box 21, Folder 392)
  - 1977 datebook (Box 21, Folder 393)
  - 1978 datebook (Box 21, Folder 394)
  - 1979 datebook (Box 21, Folder 395)
  - 1981 datebook (Box 21, Folder 396)
  - 1985 datebook (Box 21, Folder 397)
  - 1986 datebook (Box 21, Folder 398)
  - 1987 datebook (Box 21, Folder 399)
  - 1988 datebook (Box 21, Folder 400)
  - 1989 datebook (Box 21, Folder 401)
  - 1993 datebook (Box 21, Folder 402)
  - 1994 datebook (Box 21, Folder 403)
  - 1995 datebook (Box 21, Folder 404)
  - 1996 datebook (Box 21, Folder 405)
  - 1997 datebook (Box 21, Folder 406)
  - 1999 datebook (Box 22, Folder 407)
  - 2000 datebook (Box 22, Folder 408)
  - 2001 datebook (Box 22, Folder 409)
  - 2002 datebook (Box 22, Folder 410)
  - 1973 datebook (Box 22, Folder 411)
  - 1986 notebook (Box 22, Folder 412)
  - "Subject to Change" 1986 notebook (Box 22, Folder 413)
  - "Book 1 1987" notebook (Box 22, Folder 414)
  - "Book 2 1987" notebook (Box 22, Folder 415)
  - "Book III March 1988" notebook (Box 22, Folder 416)
  - "Book IV June-Sept 1988" notebook (Box 22, Folder 417)
  - "Book V Sept 1988-Jan 1989" notebook, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 418)
  - "Book VI Jan-Oct 1989" notebook (Box 22, Folder 419)
  - 1996 notebook (Box 22, Folder 420)
  - 1998 notebook (Box 22, Folder 421)
  - Undated notebooks (Box 22, Folder 422-425)
  - No Brakes notebook, circa 1997 (Box 22, Folder 426)
  - Necessary Objects notebook, circa 1972 (Box 22, Folder 427)
  - Mommy Dressing notebook, circa 1998 (Box 23, Folder 428)
  - "Bloomingdales" notebook, undated (Box 23, Folder 429)
  - Subject to Change notebook, circa 1970 (Box 23, Folder 430)
  - Notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 431)
  - 1988 diary/notes (Box 23, Folder 432)
  - Diary Book 1 original, [1996?] (Box 23, Folder 433)
  - Diary Book 3 original, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 434)
  - Diary Book 3 edited version, undated (Box 23, Folder 435)
  - Diary Book 4 original, undated (Box 23, Folder 435a)
  - Diary Book 5 edited 1988-89, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 436)
  - Notebook 1987-88, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 437)
  - Diary Book 5 partial draft, undated (Box 23, Folder 438)
  - Diary Book 4 edited version, undated (Box 23, Folder 439)
  - Loose notes, 1976-1978, undated (Box 23, Folder 440-443)
  - Phone book, undated (Box 23, Folder 444)
  - Journals, undated (Box 23, Folder 445-448)
  - Journals, undated (Box 24, Folder 449-451)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1957 (Box 24, Folder 452)
- Other Papers, 1940-2002; Series V; 5; (5 boxes)
  Series V consists of personal papers and subject files relating to Lois Gould's personal and professional life. Files include drafts of writings, printed material, correspondence and other material relating to the subject. Personal papers include correspondence.
  - Activism
    - Baby M, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 453)
    - Equal Rights Amendment movement, 1973-1984 (Box 25, Folder 454)
    - Steinberg Case, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 455)
    - Women's writers letter to New York Times Book Review, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 456)
  - Agents
    - Carol Rinzler, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 457)
    - Rob McQuilkin, 1999-2001 (Box 25, Folder 458)
  - Appearances, 1973-2001 (Box 25, Folder 459-462a)
    Includes audiocassette titled "Lois Gould ESCASAP 'The Adolescent Girl,' 1978 October 6."
  - Articles about Lois Gould, 1965-1998 (Box 25, Folder 463-465)
  - Author's Guild, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 466)
  - Biographical info, undated (Box 25, Folder 467)
  - CBC-FM Network Ideas, "Pornography and Romance," Program 4, reel-to-reel audiotape, 1979 April 12
  - Center for Research on Women, 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 468)
  - Courses, undated (Box 25, Folder 469)
  - Critique of Robert Gould article, undated (Box 25, Folder 470)
  - Cuba, 1998, undated (Box 25, Folder 471)
  - Garcia, Linda. Thesis on Lois Gould, 1981-1993 (Box 25, Folder 472-473)
  - India, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 474)
  - Insider newsletter, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 475)
  - Lists, undated (Box 25, Folder 476)
  - Pandora's box - game, circa 1976 (Box 26, Folder 477-480)
  - Correspondence about articles, 1976-1999 (Box 26, Folder 481)
  - Correspondence about books, 1961-1993 (Box 26, Folder 482)
  - Newsday list of columns, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 483)
  - Poetry by Lois Gould, undated (Box 26, Folder 484)
  - Proposals, 1973-1994, undated (Box 26, Folder 485)
  - Representation, 1976-1981 (Box 26, Folder 486)
  - Reviews by Lois Gould, drafts and printed versions (photocopies), undated (Box 26, Folder 487-488)
  - Articles about Robert Gould, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 489)
  - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Box 26, Folder 490)
  - "Wither Women", 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 491)
  - "Women's Ink", 1977-1980 (Box 26, Folder 492)
  - "Writer's Room", 1981-1999 (Box 26, Folder 493)
  - Personal correspondence, 1973-2001, undated (Box 26, Folder 494-502)
  - Personal correspondence, 1966-2001, undated (Box 27, Folder 503-506)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 27, Folder 507-510c)
  - Condolences for Jo Copeland, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 511-512)
  - Jo Copeland, undated (Box 27, Folder 513-514)
  - Personal, 1967-1998 (Box 27, Folder 515-516)
  - Medical, 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 517)
  - Photograph proofs, undated (Box 27, Folder 518)
  - Lois Gould obituaries and tributes, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 519)
  - Roger Gould obituaries, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 520)
  - Letters to Lois Gould, 1977-1993 (Box 28, Folder 521)
  - Personal letters to Roger F. Gould, undated (Box 28, Folder 522)
  - "Ultra personal" correspondence, 1982-2001, undated (Box 28, Folder 523)
  - High school yearbook, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 524)
  - Autograph books, 1940, undated (Box 28, Folder 525)
  - Business correspondence, 1967-2001, undated (Box 28, Folder 526-529)
  - Early published newspaper articles, drafts and clippings, undated (Box 28, Folder 530)
  - Unidentified drafts, undated (Box 28, Folder 531-533)
  - Copy of Congressional Record with article by Lois Gould, 1956 April 12 (Box 28, Folder 534)